this might appear to be a normal
original Xbox but what's inside it is
haha from normal now lots of people have
done pcs in an Xbox chassis before and
for being honest the finish on some of
those is better than what we've done
here but every other project we've found
either compromised on the form factor
like adding more space to the bottom or
compromised on the performance with most
of them rocking a mid tier gaming
graphics card at best well compromise is
not the Linus tech tips way we will
settle for nothing less than the first
Xbox with support for real-time rate
racing nothing less than the fastest
Xbox ever getting all that performance
in here wasn't easy though so let's take
a look at what it took to make our
latest sleeper PC Patrice brought to you
by our sponsor madrenas madrenas coffee
blend specialty cold brew coffee Xin 215
ounce grab-and-go cans for everyone's
convenience check them out and use offer
code Linus to save 40%
we'll have that linked below
[Music]
so the very first thing we need to do is
just make sure that everything that we
have here fits so we have this g-force
our TX 2070 from ZOTAC and it it should
fit in like I did some CAD and
everything fits in theory but we have I
think three millimeters of space on the
side so wow that's a really long screw
for those of you freaking out we got
this xbox in non working condition for
ten dollars so don't stress out about us
destroying vintage gaming hardware this
assembly was about what you'd expect
inside
the Xbox one not to be confused with the
Xbox one is basically a normal computer
with the majority of the internal space
being used for a disc reader and a
mechanical hard drive well we won't be
meeting either of those anymore let's do
a test fit for this sleeper we'll be
using one of Zoet acts epic mini
graphics cards in this case an RT X 27 T
and a core i5 8400 six core CPU now
compared to some of our other sleepers
Patrice's performance isn't as
over-the-top but we're working with a
passively cooled HD Plex power supply
and we wanted to save as much of our
power budget as possible for the
graphics card besides we figured chances
are anything more powerful would have
thermal throttled anyway it seems like
everything will fit we just need to make
sure it all works together and more
importantly that our power supply is
actually able to handle it all so don't
mind the mess at this stage this is just
for testing purposes power there I'm
short at the pins and no hello
yeah it's passed test number one but we
do need to get a monitor and keyboard
and make sure that it's actually I was
like run Windows and crap so we got into
Windows no problem everything's working
that's kind of expected but the real
test here is when I hit start it might
shut down and if it does we're gonna
have to rethink the whole thing so
so far so good how are you gonna get all
of that stuff in there that's the thing
I want to discuss with you so poorly is
basically the answer that's not an
answer well it kind of so we can do two
things we can either have it be really
powerful yeah or look good on the inside
and I don't think there's a way to have
both of those things okay
sleepers let's bring it back to cars Mme
so sleepers have to look bone stock from
the outside that we agree on and
sleepers have to be just head turning we
fast off the line
yeah is there any rule that says they
have to be gorgeous inside no then I
guess we know what to do
you're gonna need ventilation holes on
the bottom of the case yeah okay like
you're gonna need to cut away the bottom
of the case pretty much yeah you might
have to achieve up a bit of this plastic
shroud as well in fact you just remove
it and move it yeah yeah I mean what's
it what's even do other than look cool
yeah yeah I think we need to go in that
way then we have the perforation in the
bottom this thing shouldn't even
overheat perfect her act cuz we're gonna
perf or eight and that's my cue to exit
goodbye our methods for C and seeing
sheet aluminum have improved
significantly since our previous attempt
in Margaret we now have a single flute
end mill and double-sided tape that
doesn't gum up the bit giving us
excellent results this means that we
should end up with perfect mounting
points for our hardware and much better
rigidity compared to the paper thin
metal that's currently in here off
camera I did a prototype Bend with with
our little Vice break here and it's we
could just but it's not good enough no
so we have a solution okay
I took the credit card
and we we got a we got a really big
thing that's going over here do you want
to do you want to come oh that kind of
solution is this safe how are you
supposed to move these things oh that's
why you guys are all here
okay ah okay how much was this like 800
bucks wow that's actually not as bad I
was expecting exchange just based on the
weight yeah no it was actually very on
sale we got a good deal I wanted to buy
the three thousand dollar one all right
well then in that case good work Alex
all right fun fun fun actually this is
not that bad six people wait so this
countertop is gonna be basically
unusable for like weeks months who
signed off on this um you said you don't
care that's the actual quote of what you
said about it alright okay hold on so
you guys go ahead and come out why do
you get the coolest toys around here
Brandon also gets really cool toys
that's true but I think this one's
cooler and how do you pick the angle you
want your eyeball immolate it kind of
eyeball it okay and then you unlock it
down and then uh boom there you go you
done bent some metal there boy so for
bending sheet metal kind of the best way
to do it is to use this what they call
blue layout dye and that lets you come
in you just cover it it dries really
fast and you can scribe directly on it
and get this super high contrast and
also very precise line we have a plan
here that just tells us all of our
dimensions where the bends need to be
and also I've numbered each Bend because
like if you bend let's say number six
before number one you won't be able to
complete it because the bend will hit
the rest of that as it goes around since
the part wasn't designed with this break
in mind a couple of the bends were
pretty sketchy
vitu got all of the critical dimensions
correct and was miles ahead of the
previous prototype so we consider it a
success the next step was a test fit and
oh no don't worry mr. Linus so it was at
this point that we confirmed the stock
fans and shroud from our graphics card
would need to be removed while he was at
it Alex replaced the original thermal
paste with some crown OTT since we're
gonna need all the help we can get when
it comes to cooling with our replacement
liner prepared the old liner was
forcibly removed and all of the old
mounting needs to come out now with lots
of dremel and oh wow that fits like a
glove now you have to make some holes
for the motherboard and GPU there yeah
this is this is really the point of no
return right here like the stuff on the
inside you can't tell but if I screw
this one up geez we're just we're just
done first the bulk was removed with a
cutting disk then Alex brought it closed
with a grinding bit finishing off with a
file for a nice smooth cut so uh what's
about to happen is not for the squeamish
so the DVI connector here it goes in
like this and unfortunately it kind of
interferes with where the power
connector is going to be ten out of ten
would not recommend doing this to your
GPU
but now DVI connector list card got
blown out with compressed air to ensure
that no metal shards would shorted out
then it was taped up and reassembled but
that actually wasn't the end of the
carnage for this poor thing the i/o
shield needed to be first flattened out
and then cut down to size to fit into
the extremely small space we have for it
next all of the holes that we needed in
the bottom of the case were drilled out
and a fan intake was cut into the bottom
a hole was added for the power connector
not because this is the best time for
that step but rather because we forgot
to do it before and then the sheet metal
interior was ready to be riveted
together we're actually getting pretty
close to final product here so the blue
layout dye that was covering it was
removed with acetone and then our liner
was given a coat of black paint while
that dried the hole for the GPU i/o was
created with the Dremel and we were
ready for a real test fit since the
original GPUs fans ended up being too
big smaller ones were added using zip
ties fitting everything in a case like
this is difficult even with
purpose-built parts as for our machine
well everything does have its place but
getting it in is another story like the
GPU is so close to the motherboard that
even the i/o cover needed to be removed
for it to all fit but lo and behold
everything did fit now it's just time to
make sure that it all still works oh
nice like it's showing up over there oh
wow it just worked I honestly wasn't
expecting it to just work I figured I'd
have to do at least one little kajigger
ring damn that's that's not the power
button look I didn't have an Xbox
already that can be controlled right
yeah like that can be dialed back yeah
if you want it to be full-blown sleep or
you can just be like Kabam okay is it
supposed to be green yeah okay I'm
enjoying this
it's not especially quiet I wouldn't
describe it as crazy loud either though
and the exhaust system that you've built
such as it were does seem to be working
like there's definitely warm air coming
out so let's see what kind of
performance we can expect out of this
thing a hundred and thirty-two 160 fps
not bad
get that glory kid oh so we're seeing 84
degrees 96 percent GPU usage though so
we're definitely hitting it hard
and then our core clock is here here is
in like the 1413 high 14 lows okay so
it's like a radar base should we hook it
up in its new home
sure so right down here guys we've got
the Xbox one x vs you could call this
like an x-box you know it's got that X
Factor
it's Patrice Patrice sure apparently the
One X runs at 60fps what compromises are
they making here I mean the Xbox one X
is what like an RX 480 or something like
that well okay so fine the Xbox 1x runs
at a higher frame rate and is probably
less buggy than the PC version okay
that's not shut up you're in a field
there's like four trees
[Music]
Oh God so this is a little overpowered
for most like local multiplayer PC
gaming experiences isn't it
are you saying we should have put less
power in it I'm saying the power we put
in it might have been unnecessary oops
oh I know I would meant to I meant to
put it down in my hand or in this this
is this is just hard to this is hard to
watch Oh have you slide X I believe yep
that works okay cool I can't believe
they saved that they're better than us
so far but they're not very good I can't
find the ball I like doesn't really have
no idea for the ball they quit we're
that bad and we still won this is gonna
be awesome once we have this like all
set up and everything I mean this aspect
of it is basically good to go like we
can't plug wired controllers in from the
front we've got Wireless Xbox controller
so any you can use any kind of
controller you want because if someone
wants a ps4 controller or whatever they
can just plug in a wire like this is
freaking awesome and it's so stealth
it's our most useful sleeper ever so
we've got one terabyte of storage now
because we're using a one terabyte m2
boot drive but I suspect we're gonna
want to add a larger game library I mean
the worst case scenario is we grab an
external port terabyte hard drive and
plug it into USB 3 is that resolution
just you can't set any other resolution
you know what I bet if we just exit the
game again and try again like rocket
League it'll just it'll just get its act
together this is like really not a great
sales pitch for PC gaming it's really
great after you
a config file and then you I'm just
seeing if it has that no I don't see an
obvious wait I doubt it
oh all right oh heck yeah here we go
okay ah I can't do this on the console
yeah you wouldn't want to cuz it's a
really really bad experience but 3840 by
2160 fullscreen I bet I have to change
that to true okay let's just see if
there's anything else we should probably
change in here that all looks fine piece
of gaming find the parameters change the
parameters and then oh it's time to go
to bed you missed out on your gaming
time tonight that looks better you hook
dammit why is this necessary
oh that looks so much better that was
worth it
yes okay ah campaign yeah sure I don't
understand what weapon I had oh I have a
flamethrower oh cool nice do you that
Cleo Pete yes yeah Oh doesn't make a
difference like do all the guys have
different wet yeah they do
did you kill me guy god you killed just
the whole like MacGyver throws dynamite
okay well I didn't know
[Music]
there you have it we built the world's
most powerful gaming Xbox take that
Microsoft there were some anomalies with
Forza but we're gonna blame we're gonna
blame Microsoft for that they stack the
deck in their favor so all that's left
then is to tell you about today's video
sponsored freshbooks is the small
business accounting software that's
custom-built for how you want to work
it's a simple way to be more productive
more organized and to get paid faster if
you're a freelancer or if you're
self-employed you can create and send
professional-looking invoices in less
than 30 seconds you can set up online
payments with just a couple of clicks to
get paid up to four days faster you can
see when your client has seen your
invoice to put an end to the guessing
games and this is really cool you can
take the whole experience with you on
the go with their fully featured apps
for both Android and iOS so don't take
my word for it try out fresh books today
they offer an unrestricted 30-day free
trial if you just go to fresh books calm
slash tech tips we're gonna have that
linked below just make sure you enter
Linus tech tips into how did you hear
about us section so thanks for watching
guys if you disliked this video you can
hit that button but if you liked it for
its sheer awesomeness then go ahead hit
that like button get subscribed or maybe
consider checking out where to buy the
stuff we featured at the link in the
video description I mean yeah not this
specifically but like I don't know ZOTAC
have super compact graphics cards and
we've used them for all kinds of cool
stuff at this point ah so you can go
check those out also linked in the video
description our merch store which has
cool shirts like this one and our
community forum which you should totally
join oh really
brofist this game is pretty fun we
should play some more later